Guide to the Frey Family Papers 1793-1917 (Bulk 1825-1890) MS 235
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Drafts, 1799, 1852, undated
  Drafts for Samuel Ludlow Frey's, The Story of Our River and The Colonel and the Major. Also a draft of an article probably written by Frey, "Were They Mound Builders," and a brief, early essay of his (possibly for school) entitled "Old, times." Drafts of writings in the hand of John Frey discuss politics, slavery, homeopathy, and insurance. This series also includes what appear to be drafts of addresses, in the hand of John Frey. Topics include temperance, farming and agriculture, slavery, religion, politics, and education. As one document names Frey as recorder for an unnamed society, these addresses are not necessarily his own work. In addition, three drafts of works by unidentified authors are located in this series.
  - Drafts: SLF, The Colonel and the Major, Ch. 1-2, Undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Colonel and the Major, Ch. 3-4, Undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Colonel and the Major, Ch. 5-6, Undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Colonel and the Major, Ch. 7-8, Undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Colonel and the Major, Ch. 9-10, Undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Colonel and the Major, Ch. 11, Undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Story of Our River, Ch. 1-3, Undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Story of Our River, Ch. 4-5, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Drafts: SLF, The Story of Our River, Ch. 8-9, Undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Drafts: [SLF], others, 1852, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Drafts: bulk [John Frey], Undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Drafts: addresses, bulk [John Frey], 1799, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Drafts: addresses [John Frey], Undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Series XII. Notes, Memoranda and Extracts, 1849-1891, undated
  Many of the loose sheets are unidentified. They include extracts from plays, speeches, newspapers; quotations; axioms; religious notes; fragments of writings on various topics; lists; exercises. Notes attributed to Samuel Ludlow Frey have been previously separated. They consist of notes about history and books; quotations; and extracts.
  Bound notebooks include Samuel Ludlow Frey's "Flora of Palatine"; an unidentified volume containing "Speech of Hon. Hen. Wilson," and religious reflections and notes; an unidentified volume containing notes on the history of upstate New York; Mary Tank's notebook of pressed flowers; and a blank notebook belonging to John Frey.
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts, Undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts, Undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts, Undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts: [John Frey], Undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts: [Samuel Ludlow Frey], Undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts: [Samuel Ludlow Frey], Undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts: [Samuel Ludlow Frey], Undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Notes, memoranda, extracts: [Samuel Ludlow Frey], Undated (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Notebook: Mary Tank, pressed flowers, 1849 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Notebook: Samuel Ludlow Frey, "Flora of Palatine", 1875-1891 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Notebook: unidentified, "Speech of Hon. Hen. Wilson," religious reflections and notes, Undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: unidentified, historical notes of upstate New York, Undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Notebook: John Frey, blank, Undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Series XIII. Gold Mine Documents, 1844-1866
  This series includes documents relating to Henry A. Frey's involvement in a gold mining venture in South Carolina, including gold bullion deposit receipts, copies of indentures, articles of agreement, leases, and surveys.
  - Gold mine documents, 1844-1866 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Series XIV. Newspapers, Clippings and Reprints, 1860-1907, undated
  Contains newspapers and clippings, mostly from upstate New York publications, many of which contain articles by Samuel Ludlow Frey. Also reprints of articles, most from the Utica Morning Herald, regarding Samuel Ludlow Frey, his interests, and the Oneida Historical Society.
  - Newspapers, clippings (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Newspapers, clippings (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, clippings (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers, clippings (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Newspapers, clippings (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Reprints (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Series XV. Sketches, undated
  Sketches of various unlabeled plants and flowers, a profile of a child, and a sketch presumably by Carrie Frey Winne, of the San Francisco Bay area.
  - Sketches, Undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Series XVI. Photograph, undated
  One cased daguerreotype portrait of three unidentified men.
  - Photograph, Undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Series XVII. Fragments, undated
  Blank pieces of paper, blank forms, and one flattened wax seal of an unidentified building.
  - Fragments, Undated (Box 25, Folder 3)